

Muhammad Ismail

Sr. PHP Software Engineer

+923347075645

link2ismail@gmail.com 🔀

Multan Road, Lahore Pakistan

linkedin.com/in/ismailansaribwp in

About

Having 9+ years of experience in all facets of web development, from meeting with clients to discuss their goals, research & analysis, design, development, testing and taking feedback to improve the system. Doesn't stick to the given instructions but thinks out of the box to create a better product. Good analytical and debugging skills. Having proven record of work under pressure and adaptable to new technologies.

Key Skills

- PHP
- Laravel
- **MYSQL**
- HTML & CSS
- **AWS**
- React JS
- **Next JS**
- **JavaScript**
- jQuery
- API's Development
- Linux
- **GIT**
- ElasticSearch
- Apache

Education

BSIT (07-11) | CGPA 3.04 / 4.0 Islamia University, Bahawalpur FSC (04-07) | 65%

S.E College, Bahawalpur

Work Experience

Ilsa Interactive, Lahore 2019-2023

4 years

- Wrote the API for OTA app using PHP | Laravel
- Usage of LARAVEL Schedules, Jobs and Queues
- Usage of Amazon Services, Like S3, CloudWatch, EC2, RDS
- Usage of Elasticsearch (No-SQL) for fast search
- Usage of Redis Cache
- Worked on handling servers through SSH and deployments.
- Wrote Scripts to parse XML files and HTML Strings to get the desired data as per customized format
- Usage of MicroService architect and wrote many classes to be used in different modules as followed the DRY Principle.
- DB Optimization like usage of Indexes and denormalization / normalization of the data where required
- Developed the B2C app using React with NEXT JS
- Team Management as review work / code and assigned new tasks and deployments of their work

2016-2019 DataMonster, Lahore

2.5 years

- Worked on Amazon MWS Reporting and Analysis App, wrote PHP LARAVEL SDK Libraries for amazon MWS
- Usage of PHPUNIT and other testing techniques to improve the
- Developed multi form Authentication module in VueJs and Laravel used Stripe Payment Gateway for method

2015-2016 Xoho Tech (GeeksChicago), Lahore

1.25 years

- Worked on WP network based web app named Serving Sites. Integrate new features, plugin customization and handle responsive layouts of templates.
- Usage Of PHP, Wordpress, JQuery and MYSQL
- Developed a mobile app prototype in phonegap (Serving Sites) having features like WordPress admin front-end developed in AngularJS and Bootstrap while used WP Rest API in back-end

2013-2014 Barqsol Technologies, Lahore

1.5 years

- Developed an Ajax based web app for insurance system major features are customer management, Agent management, commission management, PDF receipts generating and email notifications
- Usage Of PHP, Codelgniter, jQuery
- Worked on social web app named Field-Trip developed the modules like matching events and activities on the basis of user interest, Admin panel CRUDS, Events and Activities Searching and Listing GRID and Map view (Google Map API) and payment module for user accounts using Stripe

Languages

- English
- Urdu